3 Years Ago in Florence, Tuscany, Italy
（タクミ･アルディーニ）
ブオン･アッペティート
Buon appetito.
You've become even better than before, Takumi.
（客Ａ）腕を上げたね　タクミは
With Isami at your side, Aldini is in good hands.
イサミもいるし
こりゃ アルディーニは安泰だ
Takumi, will you go out with me?
（女性Ａ）
タクミ 私とデートに行かない？
Looking good as usual, Takumi.
（女性Ｂ）
今日もカワイイわね タクミ
お姉さんと遊びましょうよ
Why don't we have some fun?
Takumi, want to learn how to have a good time?
（男性Ａ）
タクミ とっても気持ちいいこと
知りたくなぁい？
Si, grazie.
シー　グラッツェ
I appreciate the thought,
気持ちはとてもうれしいけど
僕には やるべきことがあるんだ
but there's something I have to do.
Are you sure you can afford
to let both of them go, Bro?
（タクミの叔父）
本当に２人とも行かせちまって
いいんだな？　兄貴
Yes. Even as their father,
I can see that they're great chefs,
親の私から見ても
２人は すばらしい料理人だ
Isami Aldini
Age 13
but there is a certain something that Takumi lacks.
しかし
タクミは 心のどこかで冷めている
Takumi Aldini
Age 13
A culinary school in Japan?
日本の料理学校？
I don't get it, Uncle.
叔父さん 意味分かんないよ
どうして 今更そんなとこに…
What's the point in us attending a place like that?
We've been working here at Aldini
for eight years already.
俺たちは このアルディーニで
８年もやってきたんだぜ
（タクミの叔父）
いやいや　行って損はない
Well, there's no harm in giving it a try.
The school's top-notch and world-famous.
世界レベルで有名な学校なんだ
You can leave the restaurant in my brother's-
I mean, your father's hands.
店のことは兄貴に…
ああ お父さんに任せておけばいい
Focus on being the best chefs you can be.
思う存分 腕を磨いてきなさい
We'd be transferring into
the second year of junior high.
中等部２年から編入…
イサミはどう思う？
What do you think, Isami?
I'll go if you do.
（イサミ･アルディーニ）
兄ちゃんが行くなら行く
Takumi will surpass me in a few years.
（タクミの父親）
タクミは あと数年もすれば
私を抜き去るだろう
But he doesn't have a goal beyond that.
だが その先の目標を
見付けられずにいるんだ
What he needs right now is a worthy rival.
今必要なのは 競うべきライバル
There's no way I can lose to any chef my age.
（タクミ）同年代の料理人に
負けるわけにはいかない
I'm a professional who has fought on the front lines.
俺はもう 食の現場で戦っている
プロの料理人なんだ
I wasn't expecting to transfer here,
（幸平創真(ゆきひらそうま)）思いがけず
編入することになったんすけど―
but I don't plan on losing to folks
who've never served a single customer.
客の前に立ったこともない連中に
負けるつもりはないっす
Anyway, what I'm getting at is...
まあ 何が言いたいかと言うと―
I just want to make it clear that
ま 要するに入ったからには―
the number one spot is mine!
てっぺん取るんで
Mezzaluna.
（タクミ）メッザルーナ！
Tritare!
トリターレ！
エヘッ
んんんっ があーっ！
Tre...
（タクミ）
トレ(３) ドゥーエ(２) ウーノ(１)
Duo...
Uno...
（タクミ･イサミ）フィーネ
Fine!
You've introduced core elements of Japanese cuisine
（乾日向子(いぬいひなこ)）
合鴨(あいがも)とサルサ･ヴェルデ
into both the duck and the salsa verde,
それぞれに
和風のエッセンスをちりばめて―
pulling it all together into
an exquisite Japanese dish.
見事に日本料理として
まとめ上げている
Takumi Aldini and Isami Aldini,
タクミ･アルディーニ
イサミ･アルディーニ
you have passed my test.
合格とします
Grazie!
（タクミ･イサミ）グラッツェ
The Batter to Adorn the Mountains
They're way too fast!
（女子生徒Ａ）早すぎる
They had to dress the duck too.
（男子生徒Ａ）
鴨をさばく手間もあったのに
１時間 かかってないなんて
I can't believe they didn't even take an hour!
Well, Yukihira Souma?
さて 幸平創真
You don't seem to have made much headway.
そちらは作業が
進んでいないようだけど
What are you going to prepare for us?
一体 何を作ってくれるんだい？
I see.
なるほど　お２人は
勝負すると言っていましたね
You said you were competing with each other.
よろしい
Very well.
If I can expect a dish that will be on par with what I just tasted,
先程の品に並ぶほどの味が
期待できるなら―
I will make an exception and judge which of your dishes is better.
どちらの料理がおいしいか
特別に審査してあげます
Did you hear that, Yukihira?
聞いたか 幸平
Sure! Let's do this!
おう！　やってやろうじゃねえか
Good. Whoever loses must kneel.
では 負けたほうは土下座を
Huh?
Loser
Kneel before the victor,
相手の目の前で土下座して―
Loser
and say "I am a loser" three times.
“僕は負け犬です”と
３回唱えましょう
Loser
If you're staking the reputation of your restaurants,
店の名を懸けて勝負するなら
これくらいの重みがなければ
then the penalty for losing
must be at least that heavy.
Oh, but you don't have to kneel,
（乾）あっ でも…
（田所恵(たどころめぐみ)）あ…
あなたは土下座しなくていいですよ
田所恵さん
Tadokoro Megumi-san.
You have such beautiful hands.
指 きれいですね
Sh-She really scares me!
（恵）こ… この人 なんか怖い
Anyway, I dare you to make
a dish that surpasses ours!
とにかく 俺たちを超える料理
作れるものなら作ってみろ！
フン
These two made no assumptions coming into this.
（創真）
こいつら 先入観を持つことなく
合鴨という選択肢にたどり着き―
They decided on a duck dish
and assembled an impressive list
of ingredients that would enhance it.
更にそれを引き立たせる食材を
ズラリとそろえてみせた
Think.
考えろ　今 この場所で―
What's the best possible dish
I can make, here and now?
俺が作れる最高の品は何だ？
Use the ingredients there
（乾）ここにある食材を使って―
to make a dish that could serve as
a main course in Japanese cuisine.
日本料理でメインとなる
ひと品を作ることです
There were chickens and rabbits too.
エリア内には鶏やウサギもいたぜ
Tadokoro.
（創真）田所
（恵）はい
Yes?
I'd like to use these ingredients
for the accompaniment.
付け合わせに
この食材を使いてえんだ
I want you to gather them.
採ってきてほしい
Think you can find all of this?
見分けつきそうか？
Um, yeah.
ええと… うん　大丈夫だと思う
I think I can do it!
I often foraged for mountain
vegetables back home.
田舎で
山菜採りとか よく行ってたから
Great.
おし 頼んだぜ　田所
I'm counting on you, Tadokoro!
But what will you be doing, Souma-kun?
創真君はどうするの？
There's something else I need to track down,
俺も探したいものがあるから
もう１回外に
so I'm heading out again.
Oh, but before I do...
…と その前に
乾先輩 ここにあるものだったら
何を使ってもいいんすよね
Inui-senpai.
You said we can use anything we find, right?
What?
えっ？　あっ はい
Oh, yes.
As long as it's within the fenced-off area.
柵の中のエリアにあるものなら
何でも
Then the key ingredient for our dish will be...
だったら 俺たちが作る料理の
鍵になる食材は…
this!
（創真）こいつだ！
（乾）あっ
Huh?
Wha—
そっ… それは！
That's—
No!
The snack I'm having with my tea!
私のお茶受け～っ！
K-Kaki rice crackers?
か… 柿の種？
So anyway, we're going outside again.
つうわけで
俺ら また行ってくっから
Oh, can you hang onto this for me?
あっ これ預かっといてくんねえ？
Huh?
は？　なんで俺が
Why me?
All right! Let's go, Tadokoro!
（創真）おっしゃ 行くぞ 田所！
（恵）はっ はい！
O-Okay!
Wait!
Boo
My kaki rice crackers!
私の柿の種…
Boo
Yukihira...
（タクミ）幸平…
What do you have up your sleeve?
一体 何を考えている
And that's the last thing on this list!
これで 私のほうは全部そろった
よ… よっ…
イテッ！　この チクショウ
Ow!
Damn you!
If there are chickens running around, that means...
（創真）
鶏が放されてるってことは…
There!
あった　ヤローッ！
Yeah!
Freshly laid eggs!
産みたてホヤホヤの卵！
（鶏の鳴き声）
This tastes terrible.
おいしくないです　やり直し
Try again.
（生徒たち）
ううっ　通る気がしねえ
Are we ever gonna pass?
（男子生徒Ｃ）これだけ挑んで
まだ 数組しか合格できないなんて
So many have tried already,
but only a few pairs have passed.
（男子生徒Ｄ）どうすりゃいいんだ
What should we do?
（男子生徒Ｅ）乾日向子
遠月(とおつき)学園 第80期卒業生
Inui Hinako.
An alumna of Tohtsuki's 80th graduating class.
In her student days, she was known
as the Empress of Mist.
在学時代は“霧の女帝”と呼ばれ
恐れられたという料理人
Everyone feared her.
The Empress of Mist?
（男子生徒Ｆ）霧の女帝？
I have no idea what that means,
but it sounds impressive.
（男子生徒Ｇ）
よく分からんが すげえ
Who gave her that nickname?
（男子生徒Ｈ）名付けたの誰だよ
はぁ…　それにしてもあれですね
In any event, I must say...
There's been so many grilled fish.
魚の焼き物ばかりで どうしても
食感が似通ってしまいます
Everything has the same texture.
I'm in the mood for something with more bite.
歯ごたえのある品が
欲しくなってきました
That's easy for her to say.
（男子生徒Ｉ）
んなこと言われたって
こんな山の中じゃ…
We're in the middle of nowhere!
What are we supposed to make?
（女子生徒Ｂ）
一体 何を作れって言うのよ
あっ 時間切れまで
何度でも作り直してかまいませんよ
Oh, you're all welcome to keep
making new dishes until time's up.
（男子生徒Ｊ）
んっ クソッ　やり直すぞ！
Sh-Shit! Let's try again!
It's hopeless!
（男子生徒Ｋ）
もう無理だよ　間に合わねえよ～
There's no time!
I sure am glad we passed, Bro.
僕たち 合格できてよかったね
兄ちゃん
Why isn't Yukihira back yet?
まだ戻らないのか 幸平は
時間がなくなってしまうぞ
He'll run out of time!
You should calm down.
とりあえず落ち着きなよ
If he doesn't finish in time, you'll win by default. What's the problem?
時間切れなら
兄ちゃんの不戦勝だからいいじゃん
I want a heated battle!
俺は熱い勝負を望んでいるんだ
不戦勝なんて認めない！
A win by default is worthless to me!
Besides,
（タクミ）
それに いきなり預けられたこれ
this thing he just handed to me...
Just how does he intend to use it in his dish?
あいつ どうやって
料理に使うと言うんだ
あっ 幸平！
Yukihira!
You're late.
遅い！　残り時間は
もう15分しかないんだぞ
You only have 15 minutes left!
俺と戦いもせず
失格になるつもりか！
Are you trying to get disqualified so you won't have to face me?!
Bro, you crushed it.
兄ちゃん 握り潰してる
あっ ああ ごめん
ち… 違うんだ 幸平　これは…
Ah, sorry!
I-It's not what it looks like, Yukihira!
Don't worry about it.
ああ 気にすんなよ
手間が省けた　サンキュー
You saved me some time.
Thanks.
Speaking of time, we have a whole 15 minutes.
（創真）
それに あと15分もあるじゃん
What?
何っ？
If I made my customers wait 15 minutes,
定食屋で15分も待たせたら
客がみんな帰っちまうよ
they'd all leave.
かかるぜ 田所！
Let's do this, Tadokoro!
Okay!
はい！
手間が… 省けた？
I saved him time?
Prepare the mountain vegetables.
（恵）山菜の下ごしらえ
First, trim the Devil's walking sticks.
まずは たらの芽の
はかまの部分を切り取る
Be thorough...
丁寧に… 丁寧に…
Thorough...
Once you're done, separate
the egg yolks from the egg whites.
終わったら
卵の黄身と白身を分けてくれ
Okay.
Huh?
（恵）えっ 揚げ物？
We're making a deep-fried dish?
Yup, fried river fish.
（創真）おう　川魚の揚げ物だ
But we don't have flour or potato starch.
（恵）でも 小麦粉も片栗粉も
衣になるものなんて何もないよ
There's nothing to use as batter.
You're not going to cook
without batter, are you?
もしかして素揚げにするの？
The moisture content of river fish is too high.
でも川魚は水分が多いから
素揚げには向かないんじゃ…
Frying them won't work well.
ところがあるんだなぁ
とびっきりの衣が
Don't you worry. We have the perfect breading.
River fish.
（タクミ）川魚 鶏卵 柿の種
Chicken eggs.
Rice crackers.
分かったぞ　幸平は柿の種を…
I get it now!
So that's how Yukihira's going
to use the rice crackers!
砕いて 揚げ衣にするつもりだ！
He's going to crush them
and use them as breading!
All right!
おっしゃ 完成！
It's done!
Here you go, Inui-senpai.
（創真）
どうぞ 乾先輩
冷めないうちに おあがりよ
Please try it before it grows cold.
All right, I'll have a taste.
はい　いただきます
Oh, my.
あっ 私の柿の種が
こんなすてきな揚げ物に！
My kaki rice crackers have become part of
such a lovely deep-fried dish!
What a wonderful texture!
なんてすばらしい歯ごたえでしょう
So crunchy.
ザックザク
それでいて中の身はホックホク
Yet inside, the fish is very tender.
Protected by the breading,
衣に守られ イワナの旨味が
しっかり凝縮されています
the fish's umami has been concentrated within.
（乾）柿の種自体の
味のおかげで―
And thanks to the flavor
of the kaki rice crackers,
衣からもしっかりとしたおいしさが
感じられます
the breading has its own assertive taste.
The accompanying sauce is light as air,
made from Japanese mayonnaise and kinome.
そして 添えられているのは
卵の素と木の芽のふわふわソース
Japanese mayonnaise?
（男子生徒Ｌ）卵の素って―
That's made by beating together
vegetable oil and egg yolks, right?
卵黄にサラダ油を加えて
泡立てたものだよな
And then they made a sauce with it?
（男子生徒Ｍ）
なるほど　あれをソースに
He mixed chopped kinome, which are shoots of the Japanese pepper tree,
卵の素に 塩と刻んだ木の芽
into the mayonnaise, along with some salt.
つまり
山椒の若芽を混ぜ込むことで―
He created a refreshing flavor that cuts the oiliness of the fish,
さわやかな風味が加わり
油っぽさが打ち消され―
上品な味わいを作り出している
making the dish more refined.
The creaminess that you can taste
衣のザクザク感の合間に感じる―
between the crunchiness of the breading whets the appetite.
このクリーミーな口当たりが
食欲をそそる
The fried mountain vegetables
are excellent as well.
山菜を揚げてしつらえたあしらいも
抜かりない
The visual contrast with the char is superb.
イワナとの対比が
実に目に鮮やかです
（乾）
フフフ　今まで何度か
この課題を出してきましたが―
I've assigned this task many times in the past.
I've seen some decent fried dishes without breading,
but this is the first successful attempt with breading.
素揚げならまだしも―
衣揚げをやってのけた生徒は
初めてですね
あむっ
The kaki rice crackers are embracing the char at the peak of its season.
（乾）
柿の種が 旬を迎えたイワナを
ギュッと包み込んで…
It's like a passionate embrace
with an elegant mermaid.
それは さながら 清廉(せいれん)な人魚への
情念に満ちた熱い抱擁(ほうよう)のよう
No, I can't...
あっ… ダメ
I'm drowning in my love of kaki rice crackers!
（乾）柿の種との愛に
おぼれてしまう～っ
Where'd you come up with this idea, Souma-kun?
創真君
どうやってこんなアイデアを？
Have you heard of something called okaki-age?
日本料理には
おかき揚げってのがあるだろう？
You deep-fry ingredients in a breading of crushed okaki crackers.
砕いたおかきを
素材にまぶして揚げることで―
食感をよくしたり
味に意外性を持たせる料理だ
The crumbs are used to improve
the texture or introduce a novel flavor.
あれなら
実家で作ったことがあったからなぁ
I've made it at home before.
And that inspired you to try it
with kaki rice crackers instead?
その応用で 柿の種を使って
揚げることをひらめいたのか
That's right.
そういうこと
I call it, Yukihira-style Char Okaki-A—
名づけて
ゆきひら流 イワナのおかき揚げ…
あっ ゆきひら流 イワナの―
No, I call it, Yukihira-style Char O-Kaki-Age!
〝お柿揚げ〞だよ！
Yukihira-style Char O-Kaki-Age
You came up with that right now, didn't you?!
絶対
今 思いついただろ！
I had that in mind all along!
（創真）計算どおり
（タクミ）行き当たりばったりだ
You're just making things up as you go!
I haven't strayed from my path!
（乾）アルディーニ君は
視野を広く持ち―
Aldini-kun kept an open mind
That was just chance.
It was blind luck!
and did not overlook duck as a possible ingredient.
合鴨という食材を見逃さなかった
You were just damn lucky!
It's actually a menu item that's pretty common at Yukihira too.
一方 幸平君は
その類まれなる発想力で―
On the other hand, Yukihira-kun
drew upon his unusual creativity
to make a dish no one here could've expected.
ここにいる誰もが
思いもよらなかったひと品を―
作りあげた
Despite the constraints of time and circumstance, they both rose to the occasion
限られた条件と時間の中でも
物怖じせず―
and made a dish that they could call their own.
自分だけの料理を作り出そうとする
That is the mindset of a true professional.
これこそプロとしての気概
Yukihira Souma and Tadokoro Megumi,
（乾）幸平創真　田所恵
you have passed my test.
合格とします
Glad you liked it!
御粗末様！
Uh... Napolitan?
Wrong!
はい そこまで
Okay, time's up!
The session is now complete.
課題は以上で終了です
（男子生徒Ｎ）ふう
（男子生徒Ｏ）よかったぁ
Thank goodness.
I'm finished!
（男子生徒Ｐ）終わった…
（男子生徒Ｑ）クッソー
Shit!
Chef Inui.
（タクミ）乾シェフ
（乾）んっ？
Please make your decision.
勝負の判定をお願いします
Very well.
よろしい
I will announce the victor.
勝者は…
The one who crafted a splendid texture for the char,
（乾）
誰も思いつかなかったアイデアで
イワナに見事な食感を与えた…
using an idea no one else had.
Wait, please give me a moment.
いや やっぱり待ってください
All right, I've made my decision.
よし 決めました
The one who did not overlook duck as a possibility,
despite being thrown into an unfamiliar situation,
未知の状況でも
合鴨という選択肢を見逃さず―
and surpassed others with his choice of ingredients.
食材選びで差をつけた…
Well, on the other hand...
いや でもやっぱり…
What are they doing?
（男子生徒Ｒ）何やってんだ？
（女子生徒Ｃ）コント？
A comedy skit?
Ugh!
What is it now?
もう 何ですか
今 大事な考え事を…
I'm in the middle of something important—
What're you up to, Hinako?!
（四宮小次郎(しのみやこうじろう)）
何やってんだ 日向子！
（乾）ひいっ！
Your group of students should've been back a long time ago.
お前のグループ
もうとっくに戻らせる時間だろう
（四宮）
とにかく早く帰ってこい　バカ女！
Just get your ass back here, idiot.
S-Sorry, Shinomiya-senpai!
ご… ごめんなさい　四宮先輩
みみみ… 皆さん
急いでホテルに戻りますよ
E-Everyone, we should hurry back to the hotel!
Hey!
What's your decision, Inui-senpai?!
乾先輩 判定は？
Eek!
（乾）ビクッ… ああ そうでした
Oh, right!
I'll...
この勝負…
have to revisit that.
私の預かりとします
All right, everyone on the bus!
（乾）さあ 大至急バスに乗って！
She kept us in suspense for so long!
（創真）じらすだけ じらして…
（タクミ）判定 逃げやがった
She ducked out of making a choice!
I'm not letting this go!
納得できるか こんなの
いいか 幸平　この決着は
いつか絶対につけるぞ！
Listen up, Yukihira!
We'll settle this someday!
Sure, but how?
いいけど どうやって？
Sooner or later, I will challenge
you to a Cooking Battle.
食戟(しょくげき)を いずれ君に申し込む
Don't you dare run away.
逃げるなよ　必ず受けろ
You'll have to accept.
And that's when I will crush you!
その時こそ 君をペシャンコにする
You'd do well to hone your skills before then as best you can.
それまで
せいぜい腕を磨いておくことだぜ
また会おう　幸平創真
Until we meet again, Yukihira Souma.
Seat yourselves as far back as you can!
（乾）
奥の座席からどんどん詰めて！
さあ 行きますよ
Let's go!
So we meet again!
なあ おい…
また会ったな！
Shut up!
（タクミ）
うるさい！　話しかけるな
Don't talk to me!
What's the matter?
（創真）
どうした　ペシャンコにしねえの？
Aren't you gonna crush me?
I told you, don't talk to me!
（タクミ）
話しかけるなって言ってるだろ！
That test allowed me to take full advantage
俺が磨いてきた技術 知識を
フルに生かせる課題だった
of the knowledge and techniques I've cultivated over the years.
When I had the inspiration for my dish,
あの料理をひらめいた時
既に勝ちを確信した
I was convinced that I would win.
But he held his own.
なのに 食い下がられるなんて
Shit.
クソッ
She didn't say which dish
she thought was better.
勝敗は決していないのに
何だ この敗北感は
So why do I feel like I've lost?
This isn't over.
このままでは終わらない
いつか必ず 君を…
I will defeat you.
（創真）トラットリア･
アルディーニのタクミ… ね
Takumi of Trattoria Aldini, huh?
There's someone my age who's that good.
俺と同い年で
ここまでやれる奴がいる
If I had stayed holed up in Yukihira,
ゆきひらにこもってたら
知らないままだったのか
I never would've known about him.
（吉野(よしの)悠姫(ゆうき)）恵！　幸平！
Megumi!
Yukihira!
You made it!
無事だったか！　アハハッ
Yuuki-chan, Ryouko-chan!
悠姫ちゃん　涼子ちゃん
他のみんなは？
What about the others?
Ibusaki-kun's checking on them right now.
（榊涼子(さかきりょうこ)）
今 伊武崎君が確認取ってる
Got it. Well done.
（伊武崎峻(いぶさきしゅん)）了解　お疲れ
All the Polar Star members
made it through the first day.
極星(きょくせい)メンバー全員
初日を生き残ったってよ
（涼子･悠姫･恵）よかったぁ
Whew!
これ… 丸井は生き残ったって
言っていいのか？
Are you sure Marui made it?
He was running around in the mountains the whole time, apparently.
（伊武崎）山の中を
延々かけずり回ったらしいぜ
Oh, guess his test was similar to ours, then.
ああ
うちと似たような課題だったか
Man, I'm tired.
でも さすがに疲れたわね
I can barely move.
もうヘトヘトで動けないよ
Don't be ridiculous, ladies.
何をおっしゃいますやら
お嬢さん方
今から ごほうびタイムだよ！
We're about to reap our rewards!
Rewards?
（涼子）ごほうび？
（恵）は？
Dinner, bath, and hotel room!
（悠姫）ディナーに お風呂に 客室
I bet they'll all be extravagant and sumptuous!
きっと どれも豪華絢爛(けんらん)
超ゴージャスなんだわ
And I'm going to enjoy all of it
to the absolute fullest!
この際
全力で堪能してやるんだからぁ！
（大学生たち）ムキッ！
BUFF
（関守平(せきもりひとし)）彼らの夕食を
完成させた者から自由時間とする
Those of you who finish serving them
dinner will be allowed to have free time.
何ですか？　その人たち
Who are all these people?!
The Jouwan University bodybuilder
club is staying nearby.
近くの施設で合宿中の―
上腕(じょうわん)大学
ボディービル部の皆さんだ
The American football and wrestling clubs will be arriving soon.
間もなく
アメフト部とレスリング部も―
ここに来ることになっている
BUFF
今日の夕食 牛肉ステーキご膳だ
Our dinner today consists of a steak set.
Servings
Each of you will prepare fifty servings.
これを 各自
50食分 作ってもらう
Servings
（男子生徒Ｓ）各自50食？
（女子生徒Ｄ）今から？
Fifty servings each?!
Now?!
You've got to be kidding me!
（男子生徒Ｔ）バッカじゃねえの？
But, Sekimori-senpai!
関守先輩 私たちの夕食は？
What about our dinner?
Once you've finished preparing
fifty servings, you can make your own.
（関守）50食 上げた者から―
自分でまかないを作り
済ませなさい
Make our own?
自分で？
But what about...
私たちに…
私たちに豪華ディナーは？
What about our extravagant dinners?
There will be no such thing.
そんなものはない
You should also know that
during your training camp,
（関守）
ちなみに研修中の朝食 夕食は―
you will be preparing your
own breakfasts and dinners.
すべて各自で調理してもらうので
そのつもりでいるように
Snap
Crackle
Oh...
（涼子）ああ…
悠姫の心が折れていく音が聞こえる
I can hear Yuuki's heart breaking.
Lastly,
（関守）最後にもうひとつ
if you cannot finish serving our guests' dinner within the next sixty minutes,
60分以内に
夕食の提供を完遂できない者は―
you will be expelled on the spot.
その時点で退学とする
Begin!
（関守）始め！
（恵）あっ！
Hey, don't cut in line!
（男子生徒Ｕ）
あっ てめえ 割り込むなよ！
（男子生徒Ｖ）
モタモタしてるからだろ！
You're taking too long!
これと これとこれ
量が足りん　作り直し
This, this, and this.
The portions aren't large enough. Start over.
Seconds.
（大学生Ａ）おかわり！
（大学生Ｂ）おかわり！
Seconds!
Not full yet.
（大学生Ｃ）まだまだ！
（大学生Ｄ）あと10杯！
Ten more bowls!
Worn out...
I can't lift my arms.
（男子生徒Ｘ）腕が上がらねえ
Worn out...
I still have thirty servings left.
（男子生徒Ｙ）あとまだ30食…
もうやだ
Worn out...
I can't take it anymore!
I'm not done yet!
終わらない！　終わらない！
Not done!
（丸井）ううっ…
（伊武崎）おい 丸井　大丈夫か
Hey, Marui.
Are you okay?
（悠姫）この合宿 やっぱり地獄や
This camp is hell after all.
Food!
（大学生たち）メシ！　メシ！
Food! Food!
It's hell on Earth, all right!
（悠姫）
ほんまもんの地獄やで～っ！
Yukihira Souma, fifty servings complete!
（関守）
幸平創真 50食達成　合格！
50 Servings Complete
You pass the test!
Glad you liked it!
御粗末！
He's so fast!
（悠姫）はえ～
クソッ　遅れをとったか
Shit!
He finished before me!
45 Servings
But just wait, Yukihira!
だがな 幸平　味は俺のほうが上だ
Mine will taste better!
I think.
多分！
You, there!
そこ！　口ではなく手を動かさんか
Move your hands, not your mouth!
Yes, sir.
あ… はい！
Well, I'll be in Marui's room.
んじゃあ
丸井の部屋行ってるからなぁ！
Don't you dare!
来なくていいよ！
僕は今夜は 速やかに寝ようと…
I want to go to bed early tonight!
（大学生Ｅ）
こらぁ　まだかよ メガネ！
Hey!
Hurry up, four-eyes!
He still wants to play?
まだ遊ぶつもりなんだ
Yukihira sure has a lot of stamina.
幸平… なんてタフな奴
I said I'd wait in Marui's room,
丸井の部屋行ってるとは
言ったものの―
but I really can't do anything on my own.
先に行っても やることねえよなぁ
Large Communal Bath
I wonder if there's something on TV.
テレビ 何かやってっかなぁ
Large Communal Bath
I should just give up
akiramechatte ii no ni
Large Communal Bath
Oh, the communal bath.
大浴場
I feel I should quit
yamechae tte omou no ni
That's right!
そうだ！　先に風呂入っちまおう
I'll just take my bath before everyone else!
But I can't get myself to start running away
nigedasu koto sae dekinakute
Maybe I'll have the bath all to myself!
今なら
大浴場 貸し切りかもしれねえぞ！
I gotta go get my yukata and underwear!
さっそく
浴衣とパンツ 取ってこねえと
I keep wavering in my uncertainty
furafura furafura
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Because I lack confidence
jishin ga nakute sono sei de
Bath
Female
Male
（薙切(なきり)えりなの鼻歌）
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
Bath
Female
Male
I can't manage to bring out the true me
jibun jishin mo dasenakute
And in this vicious spiral, I keep losing my confidence
jishin nakushte supairaru
Going round and round, round and round
guruguru guruguru
But now that we've met each other
demo deaeta kara
I won't lose sight of you
mou miushinawanai yo
Large Communal Bath
As long as your smile is there, I need nothing else
egao ga areba iranai nanimo
Large Communal Bath
（えりな）あっ！
（創真）あっ …っと
Oops, sorry.
I don't need extravagant materials or gaudy decorations
gouka na shina mo hade na kazari mo iranai kara
あ… 悪(わり)ぃ
Let's get around the table and garnish our meal
shokutaku kakomou kinou no misu mo
with yesterday's failures and tomorrow's worries
fuan na asu mo soete
Really, I don't need anything
nee iranai nanimo
I don't need exquisite seasonings or stylish food arrangements
kotta ajitsuke mo shareta moritsuke mo iranai kara
Even if the taste of the tears is salty
namida no aji wa mou shoppai to shite mo
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
In the end there will always be a smile
saigo ni itsumo warau kara
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
Don't stay in
the bath too long.
Caution!
And that's my spice
sore ga supaisu
Even if your feelings can't keep up
kimochi ga tsuite ikanakute
And leave you stuck in one place
tachidomatte shimau no ni
Time doesn't wait for you
ashita wa matte kurenakute
Pit-a-pat, pit-a-pat
harahara harahara
Squeeze my hands until it hurts
itai kurai te awasete
Hold them firmly to stop their shaking
furueru te gutto osaete
It would be nice to move forward
dokidoki mune no hayasa de
At the pace my heart is beating
dondon susumetara ii na
Hold me really tight
omoikiri daite
Let's laugh to our heart's content
omoikiri waraou
As long as we're together, I need nothing else
issho ni ireba iranai nanimo
I don't need false smiles or a tough facade
uso no egao mo tsuyogari nara mou iranai kara
I'll leave the complaints about how weak my shoulders feel
chiisaku kata no yowasa no guchi mo
At the back of the shelf
tana no oku ni de mo oite
Really, I don't need anything
nee iranai nanimo
I don't need that added fragrance or artificial coloring
sono kaorizuke mo muri na irozuke mo iranai kara
Even if the raw ingredients are no longer enough
sozai no mama ja mou tarinai to shite mo
I'll always smile without any decoration
kazarazu itsumo warau kara
And that's my spice
sore ga supaisu
End
Next Episode
（乾）次回「食戟のソーマ」
10品目になります
Next time on Shokugeki no Souma,
the tenth dish:
Menu
The Heavenly Recette
The Heavenly Recette.
「至上のルセット」
It's delicious!
おいしいですよ～
Fate is the spice of life.